<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"><channel><title>EM on amardeepsidhu.com</title><link>https://amardeepsidhu.com/tags/em/</link><description>Recent content in EM on amardeepsidhu.com</description><generator>Hugo -- 0.135.0</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 06 Jan 2022 18:41:09 +0530</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://amardeepsidhu.com/tags/em/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Unable to connect to the database with SQLPlus</title><link>https://amardeepsidhu.com/blog/2022/01/06/unable-to-connect-to-the-database-with-sqlplus/</link><pubDate>Thu, 06 Jan 2022 18:41:09 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://amardeepsidhu.com/blog/2022/01/06/unable-to-connect-to-the-database-with-sqlplus/</guid><description>&lt;p>I was working on configuring a new database for backup to ZDLRA and hit this issue while testing a controlfile backup via Enterprise Manager -&amp;gt; Schedule backup. It could happen in any environment.&lt;/p>
&lt;pre tabindex="0">&lt;code>Unable to connect to the database with SQLPlus, either because the database is down or due to an environment issue such as incorrectly specified...
If the database is up, check the database target monitoring properties and verify that the Oracle Home value is correct.
&lt;/code>&lt;/pre>&lt;p>The 2nd line clearly tells the problem but since the Cluster Database status in EM was green, so it took me a while to figure it out. Issue turned out to be a missing / in the end of ORACLE_HOME specified in monitoring configuration of the cluster database. The DB home specified was /u01/app/oracle/product/11.2.0.4/dbhome_1 instead of /u01/app/oracle/product/11.2.0.4/dbhome_1 &lt;strong>/&lt;/strong>.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>agent deployment error in EM 12c</title><link>https://amardeepsidhu.com/blog/2013/06/16/agent-deployment-error-in-em-12c/</link><pubDate>Sun, 16 Jun 2013 22:34:56 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://amardeepsidhu.com/blog/2013/06/16/agent-deployment-error-in-em-12c/</guid><description>&lt;p>Yesterday I was configuring EM 12c for a Sun Super Cluster system. There were a total of 4 LDOMs where I needed to deploy the agent (Setup –&amp;gt; Add targets –&amp;gt; Add targets manually). Out of these 4 everything went fine for 2 LDOMs but for the other two it failed with an error message. It didn’t give much details on the EM screen but rather gave a message to try to secure/start the agent manually. When I tried to do that manually the secure agent part worked fine but the start agent command failed with the following error message:&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>