<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"><channel><title>OCI on amardeepsidhu.com</title><link>https://amardeepsidhu.com/categories/oci/</link><description>Recent content in OCI on amardeepsidhu.com</description><generator>Hugo -- 0.147.9</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 24 Dec 2025 19:40:12 +0530</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://amardeepsidhu.com/categories/oci/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Decoding OCI's Database Deployment Options - Part 4</title><link>https://amardeepsidhu.com/blog/2025/12/decoding-ocis-database-deployment-options-part4/</link><pubDate>Wed, 24 Dec 2025 19:40:12 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://amardeepsidhu.com/blog/2025/12/decoding-ocis-database-deployment-options-part4/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;img loading="lazy" src="https://amardeepsidhu.com/blog/2025/12/postgresql-on-oci.png">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In &lt;a href="https://amardeepsidhu.com/blog/2025/09/decoding-ocis-database-deployment-options-part3/">part3&lt;/a>, I summarized the MySQL based options available for DB deployment on OCI. In this post I will talk about the options available for deploying PostgreSQL on OCI. While one is free to run PostgreSQL as IaaS, along with other Oracle &amp;amp; non-Oracle databases, OCI offers PostgreSQL also as a managed service. Both Intel &amp;amp; AMD based flex shapes are available and it allows you to size OCPUs and memory independent of each other. Vertical scale up/down can be done on the fly. Here are some other important features:&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Decoding OCI's Database Deployment Options - Part 3</title><link>https://amardeepsidhu.com/blog/2025/09/decoding-ocis-database-deployment-options-part3/</link><pubDate>Tue, 16 Sep 2025 21:40:12 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://amardeepsidhu.com/blog/2025/09/decoding-ocis-database-deployment-options-part3/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;img loading="lazy" src="https://amardeepsidhu.com/blog/2025/09/mysql-heatwave.jpg">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>(Image from &lt;a href="https://www.mysql.com/products/heatwave/">here&lt;/a>)&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In &lt;a href="https://amardeepsidhu.com/blog/2025/07/decoding-ocis-database-deployment-options-part2/">part2&lt;/a>, I summarized the Exadata platform based options available for DB deployment on OCI. In this post I will talk about the options available for deploying MySQL on OCI. MySQL from Oracle is available in two different flavours: Community Edition which is Open Source and two types of paid editions Standard and the Enterprise Edition. Enterprise Edition comes with additional features like TDE, Enterprise backup, HA etc. Both the Standard and the Enterprise Editions come with Oracle Premier Support. As it is with the Oracle database, MySQL can also be run as an IaaS option where you provision a compute instance, attach some block storage and install/configure the edition you need. There are options available on OCI Marketplace as well.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Decoding OCI's Database Deployment Options - Part 2</title><link>https://amardeepsidhu.com/blog/2025/07/decoding-ocis-database-deployment-options-part2/</link><pubDate>Sun, 20 Jul 2025 19:03:12 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://amardeepsidhu.com/blog/2025/07/decoding-ocis-database-deployment-options-part2/</guid><description>&lt;p>In &lt;a href="https://amardeepsidhu.com/blog/2025/06/decoding-ocis-database-deployment-options-part1/">part1&lt;/a>, I summarized the options available for DB deployment on OCI and described the Base Database Service. In this post I will talk about the second group i.e. Exadata platform based services in detail and explore the possible deployment scenarios. When it comes to Exadata based options, it get a little complex as there are multiple ways to do it. To reiterate, there are two ways the deployment can be done. One is in the public cloud and another one is the private cloud (Exadata Cloud@Customer aka ExaCC) where the hardware is deployed in the customer&amp;rsquo;s data center. Let&amp;rsquo;s now explore the different offerings.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Decoding OCI's Database Deployment Options - Part 1</title><link>https://amardeepsidhu.com/blog/2025/06/decoding-ocis-database-deployment-options-part1/</link><pubDate>Sun, 29 Jun 2025 17:25:12 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://amardeepsidhu.com/blog/2025/06/decoding-ocis-database-deployment-options-part1/</guid><description>&lt;p>So, you are looking to run a database on Oracle Cloud Infrastructure (OCI), right ? Great ! But then you login, and suddenly you are faced with a whole range of services that can feel a bit&amp;hellip;overwhelming. It&amp;rsquo;s not always obvious which one&amp;rsquo;s the right fit, especially for someone new to the OCI database landscape. That&amp;rsquo;s why I wanted to start this series of posts where we will walk through all the options that OCI throws at us for deploying databases.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Extended memory VM instances in OCI</title><link>https://amardeepsidhu.com/blog/2023/09/extended-memory-vm-instances-in-oci/</link><pubDate>Thu, 21 Sep 2023 15:48:11 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://amardeepsidhu.com/blog/2023/09/extended-memory-vm-instances-in-oci/</guid><description>&lt;p>While provisioning compute instances in OCI, you may come across scenarios which need more memory and cores than what the standard shapes provide. Extended memory VMs are meant to solve that problem. Such VMs are able to access cores and memory across a single physical socket and it allows them to go beyond the limits of standard shapes. There are no additional charges for using this specific feature. Customer is charged on the basis of total number of cores and total amount of memory used.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Can’t su to oracle user</title><link>https://amardeepsidhu.com/blog/2023/01/cant-su-to-oracle-user/</link><pubDate>Fri, 20 Jan 2023 16:55:50 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://amardeepsidhu.com/blog/2023/01/cant-su-to-oracle-user/</guid><description>&lt;p>Last week, got this issue reported by a DBA that he wasn&amp;rsquo;t able to su to oracle user from root on a Oracle Base Database VM in OCI. The login of opc user worked fine and he could do sudo su to root but he couldn&amp;rsquo;t su to oracle. When he did it just came back to root shell.&lt;/p>
&lt;div class="highlight">&lt;pre tabindex="0" class="chroma">&lt;code class="language-bash" data-lang="bash">&lt;span class="line">&lt;span class="cl">&lt;span class="o">[&lt;/span>root@xxx ~&lt;span class="o">]&lt;/span>&lt;span class="c1"># su - oracle&lt;/span>
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span class="line">&lt;span class="cl">Last login: Fri Jan &lt;span class="m">12&lt;/span> 10:20:38 UTC &lt;span class="m">2023&lt;/span>
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span class="line">&lt;span class="cl">&lt;span class="o">[&lt;/span>root@xxx ~&lt;span class="o">]&lt;/span>&lt;span class="c1">#&lt;/span>
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;/code>&lt;/pre>&lt;/div>&lt;p>There was nothing relevant in /var/log/messages or /var/log/secure. I tried it for some other user and it worked fine. Then I suspected something with the profile of oracle user and voila ! The .bashrc looked like this&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>