<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"><channel><title>Windows on amardeepsidhu.com</title><link>https://amardeepsidhu.com/categories/windows/</link><description>Recent content in Windows on amardeepsidhu.com</description><generator>Hugo -- 0.147.9</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 14 Dec 2008 19:28:25 +0530</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://amardeepsidhu.com/categories/windows/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Manually booting an OS from GRUB</title><link>https://amardeepsidhu.com/blog/2008/12/manually-booting-an-os-from-grub/</link><pubDate>Sun, 14 Dec 2008 19:28:25 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://amardeepsidhu.com/blog/2008/12/manually-booting-an-os-from-grub/</guid><description>&lt;p>One of my friend today asked me about removing Linux partitions &amp;amp; GRUB (from a dual boot system) and return back to windows alone. Removing Linux involves just formatting/removing the partitions. Now to remove GRUB either do &lt;strong>fdisk /mbr&lt;/strong> from a Windows 98 bootable CD or do &lt;strong>fixmbr&lt;/strong> after booting into repair mode with Windows XP CD. But if you have none then to remove GRUB you will need some utility like &lt;a href="http://www.ambience.sk/fdisk-master-boot-record-windows-linux-lilo-fixmbr.php">this one&lt;/a> and if you reboot before doing that it might make GRUB unable to boot into Windows. It will get stuck at GRUB&amp;gt; prompt only. So there is an option: to manually boot the OS you want (ie Windows). A quick search gave link to &lt;a href="http://www.ntcompatible.com/How_to_remove_GRUB_loader_t28242.html#150012">this thread&lt;/a>. It involves few commands on the GRUB prompt:&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Get rid of your copy paste woes in Windows</title><link>https://amardeepsidhu.com/blog/2008/03/get-rid-of-your-copy-paste-woes-in-windows/</link><pubDate>Sun, 23 Mar 2008 22:19:31 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://amardeepsidhu.com/blog/2008/03/get-rid-of-your-copy-paste-woes-in-windows/</guid><description>&lt;p>I was copying some data from a DVD and it stopped in between due to some error with some file. Then I was reminded of &lt;a href="http://www.ranvik.net/totalcopy/">Total Copy&lt;/a> (A small alternate utility to Windows copy) but even thats is not much stable and you have to right click &amp;amp; drag for copy/paste.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I googled a bit and came across another small utility called &lt;a href="http://www.codesector.com/teracopy.php">Tera Copy&lt;/a>. Its just 1 MB download and replaces Windows copy/paste. It provides many options like skipping a file, resuming copy and some other stuff. A must have for all Windows users. There is a pro version too.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>