<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"><channel><title>OEDA on amardeepsidhu.com</title><link>https://amardeepsidhu.com/tags/oeda/</link><description>Recent content in OEDA on amardeepsidhu.com</description><generator>Hugo -- 0.147.9</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 27 Oct 2020 18:53:37 +0530</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://amardeepsidhu.com/tags/oeda/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Doing an Exadata mixed cells config with OEDA</title><link>https://amardeepsidhu.com/blog/2020/10/doing-an-exadata-mixed-cells-config-with-oeda/</link><pubDate>Tue, 27 Oct 2020 18:53:37 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://amardeepsidhu.com/blog/2020/10/doing-an-exadata-mixed-cells-config-with-oeda/</guid><description>&lt;p>Earlier versions of OEDA didn&amp;rsquo;t allow you to have mixed cells in the configuration i.e. High Capacity (HC) and Extreme Flash (EF). The way to deal with that configuration was that deploy the system with either HC or EF cells and then manually configure the remaining cells.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I am not sure when did it change but the newer versions allow you have mixed type of cells in a single OEDA configuration. Once you select the hardware, there is an additional option called &lt;strong>Enable Additional Storage&lt;/strong>, where you can select the other type of cells. The minimum number of cells has to be three to use this option. Also the cells that are at the bottom of the rack physically should be selected as main storage and the other cells should be added as additional storage as that is how OEDA builds the configuration files.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>New web based OEDA for Exadata</title><link>https://amardeepsidhu.com/blog/2018/11/new-web-based-oeda-for-exadata/</link><pubDate>Wed, 21 Nov 2018 14:47:18 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://amardeepsidhu.com/blog/2018/11/new-web-based-oeda-for-exadata/</guid><description>&lt;p>It started with an xls sheet (that was called dbm configurator) . Then OEDA (Oracle Exadata Deployment Assistant) was introduced that was a Java based GUI tool to enter all the information needed to configure an Exadata machine. Now with the latest patch released in Oct, OEDA has changed again; to become a web based tool. It is deployed on WebLogic and comes with some new features as well. SuperCluster deployments will continue to use the Java based OEDA tool.  The new interface has support for Exadata, ZDLRA and ExaCC. It is backward compatible and can import the XMLs generated by older versions of OEDA. Some of the new features include the ability to configure single instance homes, create more than 2 diskgroups, create more than 1 database homes and databases, allow ILOMs to have a different subnet etc.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>OEDA&amp;ndash;Things to keep an eye on</title><link>https://amardeepsidhu.com/blog/2016/09/oeda-things-to-keep-an-eye-on/</link><pubDate>Thu, 08 Sep 2016 15:44:15 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://amardeepsidhu.com/blog/2016/09/oeda-things-to-keep-an-eye-on/</guid><description>&lt;p>So if you are filling an &lt;strong>OEDA&lt;/strong> for Exadata deployment there are few things you should take care of. Most of the screens are self explanatory but there are some bits where one should focus little more. I am running the Aug version of it and the screenshots below are from that version.&lt;/p>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>On the &lt;strong>Define customer networks&lt;/strong> screen, the client network is the actual network where your data is going to flow. So typically it is going to be bonded (for high availability) and depending upon the network in your data center you have to select one out of 1/10 G copper and 10 G optical.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>