<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"><channel><title>Unix/Linux on amardeepsidhu.com</title><link>https://v2.amardeepsidhu.com/categories/unix/linux/</link><description>Recent content in Unix/Linux on amardeepsidhu.com</description><generator>Hugo -- 0.135.0</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 20 Jan 2023 16:55:50 +0530</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://v2.amardeepsidhu.com/categories/unix/linux/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Can’t su to oracle user</title><link>https://v2.amardeepsidhu.com/blog/2023/01/20/cant-su-to-oracle-user/</link><pubDate>Fri, 20 Jan 2023 16:55:50 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://v2.amardeepsidhu.com/blog/2023/01/20/cant-su-to-oracle-user/</guid><description>&lt;p>Last week, got this issue reported by a DBA that he wasn&amp;rsquo;t able to su to oracle user from root on a Oracle Base Database VM in OCI. The login of opc user worked fine and he could do sudo su to root but he couldn&amp;rsquo;t su to oracle. When he did it just came back to root shell.&lt;/p>
&lt;pre tabindex="0">&lt;code>[root@xxx ~]# su - oracle
Last login: Fri Jan 12 10:20:38 UTC 2023
[root@xxx ~]#
&lt;/code>&lt;/pre>&lt;p>There was nothing relevant in /var/log/messages or /var/log/secure. I tried it for some other user and it worked fine. Then I suspected something with the profile of oracle user and voila ! The .bashrc looked like this&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Smokescreen detects traffic from an Exadata VM</title><link>https://v2.amardeepsidhu.com/blog/2022/03/21/smokescreen-detects-traffic-from-an-exadata-vm/</link><pubDate>Mon, 21 Mar 2022 19:30:16 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://v2.amardeepsidhu.com/blog/2022/03/21/smokescreen-detects-traffic-from-an-exadata-vm/</guid><description>&lt;p>A customer who is using an Exadata X8M-2 with multiple VMs had Smokescreen deployed in their company recently and they reported an issue that one of the Smokescreen decoy servers in their DC was seeing traffic from one of the Exadata VMs on a certain port. That was rather confusing as that port was the database listener port on that VM and why would a VM with Oracle RAC deployed try to access any random IP on the listener port. Also it was happening only for this VM. Nothing for so many other VMs.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>TNS-12543: TNS:destination host unreachable</title><link>https://v2.amardeepsidhu.com/blog/2017/07/15/tns-12543-tns-destination-host-unreachable/</link><pubDate>Sat, 15 Jul 2017 10:23:36 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://v2.amardeepsidhu.com/blog/2017/07/15/tns-12543-tns-destination-host-unreachable/</guid><description>&lt;p>Scenario : Setting up a physical standby from Exadata to a non-Exadata single instance. tnsping from standby to primary works fine but tnsping from primary to standby fails with:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>[sql]TNS-12543: TNS:destination host unreachable[/sql]&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I am able to ssh standby from primary, can ping as well but tnsping doesn&amp;rsquo;t work.  From the error description we can figure out that something is blocking the access. In this case it was iptables that was enabled on the standby server.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Manually booting an OS from GRUB</title><link>https://v2.amardeepsidhu.com/blog/2008/12/14/manually-booting-an-os-from-grub/</link><pubDate>Sun, 14 Dec 2008 19:28:25 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://v2.amardeepsidhu.com/blog/2008/12/14/manually-booting-an-os-from-grub/</guid><description>&lt;p>One of my friend today asked me about removing Linux partitions &amp;amp; GRUB (from a dual boot system) and return back to windows alone. Removing Linux involves just formatting/removing the partitions. Now to remove GRUB either do &lt;strong>fdisk /mbr&lt;/strong> from a Windows 98 bootable CD or do &lt;strong>fixmbr&lt;/strong> after booting into repair mode with Windows XP CD. But if you have none then to remove GRUB you will need some utility like &lt;a href="http://www.ambience.sk/fdisk-master-boot-record-windows-linux-lilo-fixmbr.php">this one&lt;/a> and if you reboot before doing that it might make GRUB unable to boot into Windows. It will get stuck at GRUB&amp;gt; prompt only. So there is an option: to manually boot the OS you want (ie Windows). A quick search gave link to &lt;a href="http://www.ntcompatible.com/How_to_remove_GRUB_loader_t28242.html#150012">this thread&lt;/a>. It involves few commands on the GRUB prompt:&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Unxutils for Windows</title><link>https://v2.amardeepsidhu.com/blog/2008/04/10/unxutils-for-windows/</link><pubDate>Thu, 10 Apr 2008 21:57:25 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://v2.amardeepsidhu.com/blog/2008/04/10/unxutils-for-windows/</guid><description>&lt;p>If you are used to work in Unix enviroment and then sometime, in between have to sit on Windows and tail -f alert_DB.log, its a real pain. There is a small bundle of utilities, called &lt;a href="http://unxutils.sourceforge.net/">Unxutils&lt;/a> which can make you feel at home in Windows too. These are the exe&amp;rsquo;s of all major commands in Unix like more, less, ls, grep etc&amp;hellip;&lt;/p>
&lt;p>To use it just download the zip file from the link above, extract it to some folder and add the path of exe&amp;rsquo;s to your Windows PATH. Restart your machine and you are done.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Trained in AIX…</title><link>https://v2.amardeepsidhu.com/blog/2007/11/27/trained-in-aix/</link><pubDate>Tue, 27 Nov 2007 20:56:00 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://v2.amardeepsidhu.com/blog/2007/11/27/trained-in-aix/</guid><description>&lt;p>Last week I attended a training on AIX system administration from IBM (organized by company, obviously ;) It was a 7 days course covering all of the system administration stuff. There was a lot of new stuff to learn, LVM being the most number of times uttered word, once we did the chapter on LVM. It was a nice experience as a whole as for the first time I attended any training on Unix.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Learning AWK…</title><link>https://v2.amardeepsidhu.com/blog/2007/09/17/learning-awk/</link><pubDate>Mon, 17 Sep 2007 23:24:00 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://v2.amardeepsidhu.com/blog/2007/09/17/learning-awk/</guid><description>&lt;p>I was searching for some good tutorials on awk. Found a very nice (brilliant indeed) article on Oracle website by Emmett Dulaney. A very good introduction for beginners. I searched for some other links as well. Have a read:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>1. &lt;a href="http://www.oracle.com/technology/pub/articles/dulaney_awk.html">AWK: The Linux Administrators&amp;rsquo; Wisdom Kit&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>2. &lt;a href="http://www.vectorsite.net/tsawk_1.html">A Guided Tour Of Awk&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>3. &lt;a href="http://www.softpanorama.org/Tools/awk.shtml">AWK Programming&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>4. &lt;a href="http://www.uga.edu/%7Eucns/wsg/unix/awk/#ee">UNIX Utilities - awk&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Happy awk&amp;rsquo;ing :)&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Sidhu&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Why Linux cries about "1024 cylinders thing" at the time of installation…</title><link>https://v2.amardeepsidhu.com/blog/2007/08/09/why-linux-cries-about-1024-cylinders-thing-at-the-time-of-installation/</link><pubDate>Thu, 09 Aug 2007 21:29:00 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://v2.amardeepsidhu.com/blog/2007/08/09/why-linux-cries-about-1024-cylinders-thing-at-the-time-of-installation/</guid><description>&lt;p>I have been installing Linux for last 6 years and for more than half the number of times, came across a message something like &amp;ldquo;This partitions is beyond the 1024 cylinder boundary and may not be bootable&amp;rdquo;. But never cared for it much and understood what exactly it meant to say ?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Yesterday I was reading &lt;a href="http://tldp.org/LDP/sag/html/index.html">System Admin guide to Linux&lt;/a> by Lars Wirzenius (Thanks &lt;a href="http://www.dizwell.com/prod/node/675">Howard&lt;/a> for the link :) From there I came to know what exactly that message meant. Quoting from the guide itself:&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Run levels in *nix…</title><link>https://v2.amardeepsidhu.com/blog/2007/05/14/run-levels-in-nix/</link><pubDate>Mon, 14 May 2007 23:02:00 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://v2.amardeepsidhu.com/blog/2007/05/14/run-levels-in-nix/</guid><description>&lt;p>If you are crazy@*nix, 2 really interesting posts about run levels in *nix&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="http://blogs.ittoolbox.com/unix/bsd/archives/no-runlevels-16195">No runlevels??&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="http://blogs.ittoolbox.com/linux/locutus/archives/what-is-the-use-of-runlevels-16231">What is the use of runlevels?&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>Sidhu&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Using NTLDR to boot Linux…</title><link>https://v2.amardeepsidhu.com/blog/2007/05/06/using-ntldr-to-boot-linux/</link><pubDate>Sun, 06 May 2007 09:26:00 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://v2.amardeepsidhu.com/blog/2007/05/06/using-ntldr-to-boot-linux/</guid><description>&lt;p>Sometimes, while installing Linux, installing LILO/GRUB to MBR makes you run into loads of issues, one of the most popular being that after reboot you are not able to boot into either of the OS ;) There is a way to use NTLDR to boot Linux, this way the MBR remains untouched and if you don&amp;rsquo;t want to see the Linux option, what you need to do is, edit your boot.ini and your are done.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Command line history in SQL (for Linux)…</title><link>https://v2.amardeepsidhu.com/blog/2007/05/04/command-line-history-in-sql-for-linux/</link><pubDate>Fri, 04 May 2007 20:35:00 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://v2.amardeepsidhu.com/blog/2007/05/04/command-line-history-in-sql-for-linux/</guid><description>&lt;p>Found a very interesting article on Dizwell&amp;rsquo;s blog. It was about keeping history of the SQL commands in SQL Plus on Linux. It is almost very simple. Just need to download a small utility called rlwrap from &lt;a href="http://utopia.knoware.nl/%7Ehlub/rlwrap/">here&lt;/a>. Its a tar.gz file. Download it, un-tar using&lt;/p>
&lt;p>[sourcecode language=&amp;lsquo;css&amp;rsquo;]
tar -xvf rlwrap-0.28.tar.gz
[/sourcecode]&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It will create a directory with the same name. cd to the directory and run&lt;/p>
&lt;p>[sourcecode language=&amp;lsquo;css&amp;rsquo;]
./configure
[/sourcecode]&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Running Linux from inside Windows…</title><link>https://v2.amardeepsidhu.com/blog/2007/03/16/running-linux-from-inside-windows/</link><pubDate>Fri, 16 Mar 2007 00:44:00 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://v2.amardeepsidhu.com/blog/2007/03/16/running-linux-from-inside-windows/</guid><description>&lt;p>Running Linux from right inside Windows, just like a normal application !!! Idea looks cool. I was also searching for the same thing. After little bit of Googling got one link &lt;a href="http://www.lifehack.org/articles/technology/beginners-guide-run-linux-like-any-other-program-in-windows.html">http://www.lifehack.org/articles/technology/beginners-guide-run-linux-like-any-other-program-in-windows.html&lt;/a> This article explains everything about making it possible. (Thanks Kyle Pott :)&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I had downloaded Fedore Core 7 Live CD. Tried same with this method. It is working perfectly fine. Rocking Infact !!!I have 1 Gigs of RAM in my laptop. It is giving good performance but will definitly rock with 2 Gigs.This is how it looks like on my laptop .&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>