<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"><channel><title>Utilities on amardeepsidhu.com</title><link>https://v2.amardeepsidhu.com/tags/utilities/</link><description>Recent content in Utilities on amardeepsidhu.com</description><generator>Hugo -- 0.135.0</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 10 Apr 2008 21:57:25 +0530</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://v2.amardeepsidhu.com/tags/utilities/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Unxutils for Windows</title><link>https://v2.amardeepsidhu.com/blog/2008/04/10/unxutils-for-windows/</link><pubDate>Thu, 10 Apr 2008 21:57:25 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://v2.amardeepsidhu.com/blog/2008/04/10/unxutils-for-windows/</guid><description>&lt;p>If you are used to work in Unix enviroment and then sometime, in between have to sit on Windows and tail -f alert_DB.log, its a real pain. There is a small bundle of utilities, called &lt;a href="http://unxutils.sourceforge.net/">Unxutils&lt;/a> which can make you feel at home in Windows too. These are the exe&amp;rsquo;s of all major commands in Unix like more, less, ls, grep etc&amp;hellip;&lt;/p>
&lt;p>To use it just download the zip file from the link above, extract it to some folder and add the path of exe&amp;rsquo;s to your Windows PATH. Restart your machine and you are done.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Get rid of your copy paste woes in Windows</title><link>https://v2.amardeepsidhu.com/blog/2008/03/23/get-rid-of-your-copy-paste-woes-in-windows/</link><pubDate>Sun, 23 Mar 2008 22:19:31 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://v2.amardeepsidhu.com/blog/2008/03/23/get-rid-of-your-copy-paste-woes-in-windows/</guid><description>&lt;p>I was copying some data from a DVD and it stopped in between due to some error with some file. Then I was reminded of &lt;a href="http://www.ranvik.net/totalcopy/">Total Copy&lt;/a> (A small alternate utility to Windows copy) but even thats is not much stable and you have to right click &amp;amp; drag for copy/paste.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I googled a bit and came across another small utility called &lt;a href="http://www.codesector.com/teracopy.php">Tera Copy&lt;/a>. Its just 1 MB download and replaces Windows copy/paste. It provides many options like skipping a file, resuming copy and some other stuff. A must have for all Windows users. There is a pro version too.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>