<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"><channel><title>Technology General on amardeepsidhu.com</title><link>https://v2.amardeepsidhu.com/categories/technology--general/</link><description>Recent content in Technology General on amardeepsidhu.com</description><generator>Hugo -- 0.145.0</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 20 Aug 2008 23:00:49 +0530</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://v2.amardeepsidhu.com/categories/technology--general/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Lotus notes and sametime</title><link>https://v2.amardeepsidhu.com/blog/2008/08/20/lotus-notes-and-sametime/</link><pubDate>Wed, 20 Aug 2008 23:00:49 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://v2.amardeepsidhu.com/blog/2008/08/20/lotus-notes-and-sametime/</guid><description>&lt;p>My company uses Lotus Notes for email and Sametime connect as messenger for all the internal communication. Both are stupid applications and are a big resource hogs. Most of the systems are P IV with 512 MB RAM. You just run Lotus and Sametime 7 and it eats up everything. The system moves like a 386 based machine.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Moreover, i was looking for Lotus short cuts today and found that there is no short cut in Lotus for &lt;strong>Send/Receive&lt;/strong> mail.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Solid state cooling for processors</title><link>https://v2.amardeepsidhu.com/blog/2008/03/23/solid-state-cooling-for-processors/</link><pubDate>Sun, 23 Mar 2008 11:40:52 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://v2.amardeepsidhu.com/blog/2008/03/23/solid-state-cooling-for-processors/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;a href="http://www.dailytech.com/Engineers+Develop+Solidstate+Fan+That+Puts+Traditional+Coolers+to+Shame/article11158.htm">Engineers Develop Solid-state Fan That Puts Traditional Coolers to Shame&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Cool ! isn&amp;rsquo;t it ?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Soon we may be using 5 Ghz super cool processors in our desktop box :)&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Tracing Wikipedia…</title><link>https://v2.amardeepsidhu.com/blog/2007/09/16/tracing-wikipedia/</link><pubDate>Sun, 16 Sep 2007 23:23:00 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://v2.amardeepsidhu.com/blog/2007/09/16/tracing-wikipedia/</guid><description>&lt;p>Today &lt;a href="http://www.stumbleupon.com/">Stumble&lt;/a> gave me a link to &lt;a href="http://www.maltastar.com/pages/msFullArt.asp?an=14323">an article&lt;/a> on a website. That article talks about a guy &lt;a href="http://virgil.gr/">Virgil Griffith&lt;/a> who wrote a piece of software to track IP addresses of the people, editing the &lt;a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Virgil_Griffith">Wikipedia&lt;/a> content. Some really interesting things came up: Apple attacking Microsoft and then Microsoft taking revenge. Have a look at the full article. It makes an interesting read. Read more about this guy on Wikipedia &lt;a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Virgil_Griffith">here&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Sidhu&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Plugged-in back to www…</title><link>https://v2.amardeepsidhu.com/blog/2007/08/08/plugged-in-back-to-www/</link><pubDate>Wed, 08 Aug 2007 23:32:00 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://v2.amardeepsidhu.com/blog/2007/08/08/plugged-in-back-to-www/</guid><description>&lt;p>Last to last week, we shifted to a new house. As there was no internet connection, so we were without any internet access for last 2 weeks. Today we got the new internet connection. Its a DSL one. And the guy who came to do the installation threw a little bit of technical jargon like rebooting the router and so on.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It feels so good to be back in the world of www :)&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Hats off…</title><link>https://v2.amardeepsidhu.com/blog/2007/07/04/hats-off/</link><pubDate>Wed, 04 Jul 2007 22:31:00 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://v2.amardeepsidhu.com/blog/2007/07/04/hats-off/</guid><description>&lt;p>Since I switched to this new job, my profile has changed. Here I work as a DBA. So my interaction with Oracle &amp;amp; anything related to Oracle has also increased. Started exploring Oracle related forums and websites specially OTN forums (&lt;a href="http://forums.oracle.com">http://forums.oracle.com&lt;/a>) This is the only page thats almost always open on my Desktop in office &amp;amp; Laptop at home and I refresh more than my office Lotus Notes. Today I was reading &lt;a href="http://radiofreetooting.blogspot.com/2007/07/where-does-he-find-time.html">APCs blog&lt;/a> , that Jonathan Lewis has also started posting on OTN forums and being so busy man, from where he finds the time ? I too think the same. There are so many people having many years of experience in industry, answering the questions on OTN, uesnet groups and various other forums and everything is for free. They are not paid anything for the same thing. Its like taking time out of your time, understand somebody&amp;rsquo;s problem, create same scenario your PC, try out and then post the answer ! I am, sort of new to the forums and sometimes for whole of week, I am unable to post any answers, even knowing something about the issue someone has posted. Just the &amp;ldquo;time&amp;rdquo; thing. These days I am very close to OTN forums, visit for whole of the day and also post answers to the questions I know something about. There are many people who are regular visitors and are answering questions on the daily basis. Hats off ! to all these &amp;ldquo;big bosses&amp;rdquo; of the technology !&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Utilities I cant survive without…</title><link>https://v2.amardeepsidhu.com/blog/2007/04/16/utilities-i-cant-survive-without/</link><pubDate>Mon, 16 Apr 2007 14:46:00 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://v2.amardeepsidhu.com/blog/2007/04/16/utilities-i-cant-survive-without/</guid><description>&lt;p>Well, here I am listing down the important tools and utilities I seem to use on the daily basis and without them life on internet &amp;amp; laptop really seems to be stuck, sort of :(&lt;/p>
&lt;p>1. Winamp: No need to say anything. Winamp is possibly the best and lightest mp3 (these days videos also) player. Just run Winamp in the system tray and enjoy&lt;/p>
&lt;p>2. Winrar: Utility to uncompress compressed files. Earlier winzip was my favorite but recently I swichted to Winrar as Winzip doesn&amp;rsquo;t support rar format. I am pretty happy using it.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>{ Height of } Helplessness…</title><link>https://v2.amardeepsidhu.com/blog/2007/04/01/height-of-helplessness/</link><pubDate>Sun, 01 Apr 2007 19:11:00 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://v2.amardeepsidhu.com/blog/2007/04/01/height-of-helplessness/</guid><description>&lt;p>There are times when you just can&amp;rsquo;t do anything, I repeat, you just can&amp;rsquo;t do anything. In the evening I was working on my laptop and everything was fine. Next day in the morning when I got up, switched on the laptop and clicked on IE icon, it happily gave a beautiful error message &amp;ldquo;This application failed to start because msvcrl.dll was not found. Re-installing the application may fix the problem.&amp;rdquo; So it was the time for Googling about the error. Thank God I had Opera installed. After 2-3 hits I came to know that it was a trojan. Finally, there was one dll which needed to be deleted to get rid of this error message :) But after that there was some problem with IE in opening some of the sites. One option was to upgrade to IE 7 but don&amp;rsquo;t know why, I havn&amp;rsquo;t started liking IE 7 yet. So no other option left than restoring windows (I have Windows XP Media Center Edition installed).&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Viruses, Intrusion attempts and Norton…</title><link>https://v2.amardeepsidhu.com/blog/2007/03/25/viruses-intrusion-attempts-and-norton/</link><pubDate>Sun, 25 Mar 2007 23:22:00 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://v2.amardeepsidhu.com/blog/2007/03/25/viruses-intrusion-attempts-and-norton/</guid><description>&lt;p>When I got my Laptop, along with it also got Norton Internet Security and 2 months subscription for updates &amp;amp; all. Whenever I would boot up the laptop Internet Security would open the window for configuration. I kept on cancelling it for 2 weeks or so. But one fine (read not fine :( day I configured it. It was very happy. Said &lt;strong>Thank You&lt;/strong> at the end. But the best was yet to come. After 10-15 days Windows (XP media center is installed on my Laptop) started showing signs of strain ;) It won&amp;rsquo;t start properly, after saying loading your settings it will stuck. Then I had to kill explorer.exe and start it again. With this also one strange problem that no startup items will be loaded :( I was discussing the same with one of my friend. He said that Norton must be the culprit. So I thought about uninstalling it. When I tried to uninstall it gave some strange error. Anyways it also told about one URL from where one could check details of the error. Finally when the uninstall started it gave one beautiful message &amp;ldquo;You still have 39 days of subscription left, if you uninstall the product you will not be able to reuse the subscription&amp;rdquo; :D&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Intelligent people, geeks and nerds…</title><link>https://v2.amardeepsidhu.com/blog/2007/03/19/intelligent-people-geeks-and-nerds/</link><pubDate>Mon, 19 Mar 2007 13:46:00 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://v2.amardeepsidhu.com/blog/2007/03/19/intelligent-people-geeks-and-nerds/</guid><description>&lt;p>I was checking &lt;a href="http://tkyte.blogspot.com/">Tom Kyte&amp;rsquo;s blog&lt;/a>. It was about an &lt;a href="http://nomadishere.com/2007/03/12/a-note-to-employers-8-things-intelligent-people-geeks-and-nerds-need-to-work-happy">article&lt;/a> titled A Note To Employers: 8 Things Intelligent People, Geeks and Nerds Need To Work Happily. Well first of all meaning of all three words from &amp;ldquo;define: * in Google&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>
&lt;p>1. Intelligent: having the capacity for thought and reason especially to a high degree&lt;/p>
&lt;p>2. Geek: In computers and the Internet, a geekis a person who is inordinately dedicated to and involved with the technologyto the point of sometimes not appearing to be like the rest of us (non-geeks).Being a geek also implies a capability with the technology.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>RSS Feeds…</title><link>https://v2.amardeepsidhu.com/blog/2007/03/14/rss-feeds/</link><pubDate>Wed, 14 Mar 2007 12:47:00 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://v2.amardeepsidhu.com/blog/2007/03/14/rss-feeds/</guid><description>&lt;p>For the last 4-5 months I was almost without a PC and internet. This problem was solved when I got my HP laptop last month and then internet connection this month. One thing I had heard much about was RSS feeds and also wanted to try the same because there were many blogs which I used to check regularly. I had an idea about the concept used by RSS feeds that you will need to install a piece of software on your PC, give link of the page you want it to monitor and it will inform you when there is something new since your last visit.(period) Nothing more I knew.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Small things…</title><link>https://v2.amardeepsidhu.com/blog/2006/09/27/small-things/</link><pubDate>Wed, 27 Sep 2006 16:18:00 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://v2.amardeepsidhu.com/blog/2006/09/27/small-things/</guid><description>&lt;p>sometimes even very small things mess up everything in your head&amp;hellip;something similar happened with me also&amp;hellip;had two lists of numbers&amp;hellip;some numbers were missing in one&amp;hellip;wanted to find out thoes..instead of inserting values in tables then using SQL or using diff on Unix&amp;hellip;thought about using Excel for the same&amp;hellip;much heard about function VLOOKUP is there&amp;hellip;which we can use for such scenarios&amp;hellip;so I also tried the same&amp;hellip;.had heard a lot abt vlookup but was generally heard of it&amp;hellip;as when people used to write &amp;ldquo;=vlookup(bla bla bla bla&amp;hellip;)&amp;rdquo;&amp;hellip;i just used to count my heartbeat&amp;hellip;and look around&amp;hellip;so this was the time when i really needed to learn vlookup so as a normal computer geek wud do&amp;hellip;i opened google.com and started searching the same&amp;hellip;what i got was really disappointing&amp;hellip;.everywhere i almost found the same language&amp;hellip;.(oops&amp;hellip;.i also checked microsoft help even dat techie lingo didnt help as when you have messed up the things&amp;hellip;nothing really gets into your head&amp;hellip;.)&amp;hellip;some of that text&amp;hellip;m pasting here with a hope that it wont create copyright issues&amp;hellip;.i really got nothing out of this&amp;hellip;.&lt;br>
&amp;ldquo;Searches for a value in the leftmost column of a table, and then returns a value in the same row from a column you specify in the table. Use VLOOKUP instead of HLOOKUP when your comparison values are located in a column to the left of the data you want to find.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>