<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"><channel><title>General on amardeepsidhu.com</title><link>https://v2.amardeepsidhu.com/categories/general/</link><description>Recent content in General on amardeepsidhu.com</description><generator>Hugo -- 0.135.0</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 10 Oct 2019 19:40:04 +0530</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://v2.amardeepsidhu.com/categories/general/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>OGB Appreciation Day : Thank you community ! (#ThanksOGB)</title><link>https://v2.amardeepsidhu.com/blog/2019/10/10/ogb-appreciation-day-thank-you-community-thanksogb/</link><pubDate>Thu, 10 Oct 2019 19:40:04 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://v2.amardeepsidhu.com/blog/2019/10/10/ogb-appreciation-day-thank-you-community-thanksogb/</guid><description>&lt;p>It was &lt;a href="https://oracle-base.com/blog/2019/09/30/ogb-appreciation-day-2019-thanksogb/">started by Tim Hall&lt;/a> in 2016. This is a Thank you community post. There are so many experts posting on Oracle related forums, doing blog posts, sharing their scripts with everyone. All of you are doing a great job. I would like to mention three names especially:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://oracle-base.com/">Tim Hall&lt;/a> : Tim is a legend ! I don&amp;rsquo;t consider something a new feature until Tim writes about it :D&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://jonathanlewis.wordpress.com/all-postings/">Jonathan Lewis&lt;/a> : I don&amp;rsquo;t think there is anyone on this planet who has even once worked on a performance problem and hasn&amp;rsquo;t gained something from the knowledge shared by him on forums or in one of the blog posts.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Presenting at Cloud day event of North India Chapter of AIOUG</title><link>https://v2.amardeepsidhu.com/blog/2017/11/06/presenting-at-cloud-day-event-of-north-india-chapter-of-aioug/</link><pubDate>Mon, 06 Nov 2017 17:17:07 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://v2.amardeepsidhu.com/blog/2017/11/06/presenting-at-cloud-day-event-of-north-india-chapter-of-aioug/</guid><description>&lt;p>I will be presenting a session titled &lt;strong>&amp;ldquo;An 18 pointers guide to setting up an Exadata machine&amp;rdquo;&lt;/strong> at Cloud Day being organized by North India chapter of AIOUG. &lt;a href="https://viveklsharma.wordpress.com/">Vivek Sharma&lt;/a> is doing multiple sessions on various cloud and performance related topics. You can register for the event here&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://www.meraevents.com/event/aioug-nic-cloud-day">https://www.meraevents.com/event/aioug-nic-cloud-day&lt;/a>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Sangam 15</title><link>https://v2.amardeepsidhu.com/blog/2015/11/24/sangam-15/</link><pubDate>Tue, 24 Nov 2015 19:04:30 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://v2.amardeepsidhu.com/blog/2015/11/24/sangam-15/</guid><description>&lt;p>This was my 6th year at Sangam and as always was good fun. We were a group of 4 people who were traveling from Delhi and we reached Hyderabad on Friday morning. Just wanted to keep a day for visiting &lt;a href="http://ramojifilmcity.com/">Ramoji Film City&lt;/a> and also wanted to avoid the rush that morning travel on the conference&amp;rsquo;s starting day brings. So after dropping the luggage at the hotel we hired a taxi and reached Ramoji Film City. It is a huge place and it is tiring to move around checking everything. But fortunately on that day the weather was very pleasant so moving around was good fun. We took a ride what they call as Space Walk and watched few sets where some movies were shot. Also they have a pretty good bird sanctuary over there where they have pretty good number of beautiful birds. Spending time there was nice and fun.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Sangam 10</title><link>https://v2.amardeepsidhu.com/blog/2010/09/12/sangam-10/</link><pubDate>Sun, 12 Sep 2010 16:57:12 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://v2.amardeepsidhu.com/blog/2010/09/12/sangam-10/</guid><description>&lt;p>It has been almost an year since i posted something (useful) here. The last post was also a crappy one :) . Well, it all boils down to sheer laziness ;) . Now, i think the time has come to be regular again. Here i am getting a good start talking about &lt;a href="http://www.aioug.org/sangam10.php">Sangam10&lt;/a>, i attended last week. It was a great opportunity to meet so many fellow Oracle professionals and most awesomely to meet &amp;amp; see &lt;a href="http://jonathanlewis.wordpress.com/">Jonathan Lewis&lt;/a> talk about Performance &amp;amp; Tuning. As expected the whole experience was amazing. It was a 2 day event where Jonathan was delivering 2 half day seminars on SQL Tuning and there were other break out sessions as well. We had planned to go a day in advance so me, &lt;a href="http://blog.aristadba.com/">Aman&lt;/a>, &lt;a href="http://ankitkgoel.wordpress.com/">Ankit&lt;/a> &amp;amp; &lt;a href="http://neerajbhatia.wordpress.com">Neeraj&lt;/a> reached Hyderabad on 2nd Sep.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Required ;)</title><link>https://v2.amardeepsidhu.com/blog/2009/02/23/required/</link><pubDate>Mon, 23 Feb 2009 23:42:28 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://v2.amardeepsidhu.com/blog/2009/02/23/required/</guid><description>&lt;p>On the wall just outside my office. Who says there is recession ? ;)&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img alt="required" loading="lazy" src="https://v2.amardeepsidhu.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2009/02/required.jpg">&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="comments">Comments&lt;/h2>
&lt;h3 id="comment-by-dan-norris-on-2009-02-23-234004-0530">Comment by Dan Norris on 2009-02-23 23:40:04 +0530&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Forms and Reports? For what? How old is this picture? 🙂&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="comment-by-neeraj-on-2009-02-23-235403-0530">Comment by Neeraj on 2009-02-23 23:54:03 +0530&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>cool 😀&lt;/p>
&lt;p>bulk joining leads to bulk firing ….&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="comment-by-puja-on-2009-02-24-094206-0530">Comment by Puja on 2009-02-24 09:42:06 +0530&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Just hope it is not one of those job scams that they pull on poor unemployed youth!&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>My re-designed website ;)</title><link>https://v2.amardeepsidhu.com/blog/2008/12/09/my-re-designed-website/</link><pubDate>Tue, 09 Dec 2008 20:39:40 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://v2.amardeepsidhu.com/blog/2008/12/09/my-re-designed-website/</guid><description>&lt;p>Since long time i have been struggling to learn CSS and make &lt;a href="http://www.amardeepsidhu.com">my website&lt;/a> look great. The efforts did succeed but not in a way i wanted. After playing with CSS for few months i finally switched to Joomla and yes, in a week my website looks pretty cool. CSS automated ;) . Joomla installation is pretty next-next job. Then play around a bit and you are done. Next game is to choose a nice looking template according to your taste and addition of few extensions to make yours tasks easier. (Wordpress &amp;amp; Joomla rock because of these free extensions). So after long time i feel satisfied with the way my website looks. Here are the screenshots of the old and present new look for archives ;)&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>OTN forums suck ?</title><link>https://v2.amardeepsidhu.com/blog/2008/09/14/otn-forums-suck/</link><pubDate>Sun, 14 Sep 2008 18:41:35 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://v2.amardeepsidhu.com/blog/2008/09/14/otn-forums-suck/</guid><description>&lt;p>Okay, so kids have stopped crying as they got some milk from their mommy: forums are better now (than when came back after an upgrade). There are reasons that it takes time for the things to be smooth. Fine. But what drives me mad is the way Oracle handled this and now ? The font size and those bloody bullets on left side which tell you if you have read the post before ? Please let me know if someone can interpret what those bullets tell and can read the forum without doing Ctrl + in Mozilla/Chrome and suffering from reading everything in large font size in IE 6 ?&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Conducting my first interview ;)</title><link>https://v2.amardeepsidhu.com/blog/2008/07/29/conducting-my-first-interview/</link><pubDate>Tue, 29 Jul 2008 07:19:08 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://v2.amardeepsidhu.com/blog/2008/07/29/conducting-my-first-interview/</guid><description>&lt;p>Last week i had a chance to conduct my life&amp;rsquo;s first interview. The guy was a DBA with 2 years of experience and it was supposed to be a telephonic call. I checked out his CV and wrote down around 8 questions on a paper, just to make sure that i myself don&amp;rsquo;t get confused during the interview  ;) . So i called him in the evening and started with introduction and his present job profile. Then i started with the questions from the projects he had done. He was confident about the stuff he was handling and replied all the questions honestly, saying NO at points where he didn&amp;rsquo;t know or was not involved in something. One of such thing was testing the backups. He said there is no testing done as such.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>DBAzine.com is back :)</title><link>https://v2.amardeepsidhu.com/blog/2008/03/31/dbazine-com-is-back/</link><pubDate>Mon, 31 Mar 2008 21:54:31 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://v2.amardeepsidhu.com/blog/2008/03/31/dbazine-com-is-back/</guid><description>&lt;p>Few days ago i &lt;a href="https://v2.amardeepsidhu.com/blog/2008/03/22/dbazinecom-has-expired/">posted&lt;/a> about &lt;a href="http://www.dbazine.com/">DBAzine&lt;/a> being down. I was just checking to see if its back.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Its rocking now.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Welcome back DBAzine.com :)&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="comments">Comments&lt;/h2>
&lt;h3 id="comment-by-arshad-on-2011-11-01-014603-0530">Comment by arshad on 2011-11-01 01:46:03 +0530&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>I saw your article — interesting&lt;br>
I need to know many things&lt;br>
1st of all please let me know how to&lt;br>
move (parameter, text) to word document from oracle form 6i. data is queried from table&lt;br>
i can open existing document&lt;br>
i can create new document&lt;br>
now I wanyt to move text to my document like it would had been through mail-merge&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>dbazine.com has expired</title><link>https://v2.amardeepsidhu.com/blog/2008/03/22/dbazine-com-has-expired/</link><pubDate>Sat, 22 Mar 2008 15:45:17 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://v2.amardeepsidhu.com/blog/2008/03/22/dbazine-com-has-expired/</guid><description>&lt;p>Today I was googling about Oracle Data Guard and came across an article on dbazine.com. I opened the link and it showed some stupid page. I checked again and again. Finally I noticed a message on top right:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>dbazine.com&lt;/strong> expired on 03/13/2008 and is pending renewal or deletion.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>:(&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It was a nice website.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>