<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"><channel><title>Data Guard on amardeepsidhu.com</title><link>https://v2.amardeepsidhu.com/tags/data-guard/</link><description>Recent content in Data Guard on amardeepsidhu.com</description><generator>Hugo -- 0.145.0</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 31 May 2017 21:24:54 +0530</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://v2.amardeepsidhu.com/tags/data-guard/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>ORA-12154 in Data Guard environment</title><link>https://v2.amardeepsidhu.com/blog/2017/05/31/ora-12154-in-data-guard-environment/</link><pubDate>Wed, 31 May 2017 21:24:54 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://v2.amardeepsidhu.com/blog/2017/05/31/ora-12154-in-data-guard-environment/</guid><description>&lt;p>Hit this silly issue in one of the data guard environments today. Primary is a 2 node RAC running 11.2.0.4 and standby is also a 2 node RAC. Archive logs from node2 aren&amp;rsquo;t shipping and the error being reported is&lt;/p>
&lt;p>[sql]ORA-12154: TNS:could not resolve the connect identifier specified[/sql]&lt;/p>
&lt;p>We tried usual things like going to $TNS_ADMIN, checking the entry in tnsnames.ora and then also trying to connect using sqlplus sys@target as sysdba. Everything seemed to be good but logs were not shipping and the same problem was being reported repeatedly. As everything on node1 was working fine so it looked even more weird.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>MRP process on standby stops with ORA-00600</title><link>https://v2.amardeepsidhu.com/blog/2015/08/20/mrp-process-on-standby-stops-with-ora-00600/</link><pubDate>Thu, 20 Aug 2015 14:33:45 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://v2.amardeepsidhu.com/blog/2015/08/20/mrp-process-on-standby-stops-with-ora-00600/</guid><description>&lt;p>A rather not so great post about an ORA-00600 error i faced on a standby database. Environement was 11.2.0.3 on Sun Super Cluster machine. MRP process was hitting ORA-00600 while trying to apply a specific archive log.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The error message was something like this&lt;/p>
&lt;pre tabindex="0">&lt;code>MRP0: Background Media Recovery terminated with error 600
Errors in file /u01/app/oracle/product/11.2.0.3/diag/diag/rdbms/xxxprd/xxxprd1/trace/xxxprd1_pr00_6342.trc:
ORA-00600: internal error code, arguments: [2619], [539], [], [], [], [], [], [], [], [], [], []
Recovery interrupted!
&lt;/code>&lt;/pre>&lt;p>Some googling and MOS searches revealed that the error was due to corrupted archive log file. Recopying the archive file from primary and restarting the recovery resolved the issue. The fist argument of the ORA-600 is actually the sequence no of the archive it is trying to apply.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>