<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"><channel><title>Upgrade on amardeepsidhu.com</title><link>https://amardeepsidhu.com/tags/upgrade/</link><description>Recent content in Upgrade on amardeepsidhu.com</description><generator>Hugo -- 0.135.0</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 29 Jan 2011 22:30:29 +0530</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://amardeepsidhu.com/tags/upgrade/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Issues in upgrading from 9i to 10g</title><link>https://amardeepsidhu.com/blog/2011/01/29/issues-in-upgrading-from-9i-to-10g/</link><pubDate>Sat, 29 Jan 2011 22:30:29 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://amardeepsidhu.com/blog/2011/01/29/issues-in-upgrading-from-9i-to-10g/</guid><description>&lt;p>Last week I had a chance to upgrade a 9.2.0.7 database to 10.2.0.5. The size of the database was around 800 GB. The major applications connecting to the database were developed in Pro*C and Oracle Forms. The upgrade itself pretty smooth but there were few glitches around that needed to be handled. Just thought about documenting all the issues:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Few users in the database were assigned the CREATE SESSION privilege through a password protected role (That role was the default role for that user). 10.2.0.5 onwards, password protected roles can’t be set as default roles. The alternate is to either disable the password for the role or assign CREATE SESSION directly to the user, not through a role.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>OTN forums – 2nd upgrade attempt</title><link>https://amardeepsidhu.com/blog/2008/08/28/otn-forums-2nd-upgrade-attempt/</link><pubDate>Thu, 28 Aug 2008 07:28:39 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://amardeepsidhu.com/blog/2008/08/28/otn-forums-2nd-upgrade-attempt/</guid><description>&lt;p>Well, as everybody has seen, last week they have again upgraded the OTN forums. And sadly it has been handled in a very poor manner. End result is that it is running terribly slow and throwing some errors many times. In my office, i cant even open it properly may be its too heavy or some issue with the internet. Also there has been lots of hues and cries about the new point system and all. That in my opinion is fine except that speed at which forums are running should be fine.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Upgrade to WordPress 2.6</title><link>https://amardeepsidhu.com/blog/2008/07/15/upgrade-to-wordpress-2-6/</link><pubDate>Tue, 15 Jul 2008 22:28:06 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://amardeepsidhu.com/blog/2008/07/15/upgrade-to-wordpress-2-6/</guid><description>&lt;p>Just upgraded my blog to Wordpress 2.6. There are few new things. This video from Wordpress summarizes the new stuff:&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Automating WordPress 2.5 upgrade</title><link>https://amardeepsidhu.com/blog/2008/04/06/automating-wordpress-2-5-upgrade/</link><pubDate>Sun, 06 Apr 2008 11:59:44 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://amardeepsidhu.com/blog/2008/04/06/automating-wordpress-2-5-upgrade/</guid><description>&lt;p>I recently &lt;a href="https://amardeepsidhu.com/blog/2008/03/30/upgrading-to-wordpress-25/">upgraded&lt;/a> my blog to Wordpress 2.5. The manual process is real cumbersome. Today I came across few plugins which help in almost automating the upgrade stuff.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="http://wordpress.org/extend/plugins/wordpress-automatic-upgrade/">Wordpress Automatic upgrade:&lt;/a> As per description this plugin first takes backup and then upgrades. I didn&amp;rsquo;t try this one, though.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="http://www.zirona.com/software/wordpress-instant-upgrade/">Instant Upgrade:&lt;/a> I upgraded one of my blog using this. It doesn&amp;rsquo;t take care of backup but otherwise the upgrade was super smooth. Just few clicks and you are done.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Upgrading to WordPress 2.5</title><link>https://amardeepsidhu.com/blog/2008/03/30/upgrading-to-wordpress-2-5/</link><pubDate>Sun, 30 Mar 2008 17:46:14 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://amardeepsidhu.com/blog/2008/03/30/upgrading-to-wordpress-2-5/</guid><description>&lt;p>Just finished upgrading to Wordpress 2.5. Everything seems to be working fine.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Another issue I just came to know that wherever i am using &lt;a href="https://amardeepsidhu.com/blog/2008/03/03/syntax-highlighting-for-code-in-wordpress/">syntaxhighlighter&lt;/a> to format the code, it doesn&amp;rsquo;t display properly in Internet Explorer. May be something to do with the plugin. Will try to fix it. It works fine in Mozilla.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Upgrade 10gR1 to 10gR2 – DBUA error</title><link>https://amardeepsidhu.com/blog/2008/03/27/upgrade-10gr1-to-10gr2-dbua-error/</link><pubDate>Thu, 27 Mar 2008 22:53:01 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://amardeepsidhu.com/blog/2008/03/27/upgrade-10gr1-to-10gr2-dbua-error/</guid><description>&lt;p>Today I was upgrading 10gR1 to 10gR2 (10.2.0.1) on Linux x86. The upgrade went almost fine (except that I had to install one package and change few kernel parameters) but while running DBUA to upgrade databases, it gave an error:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>[sourcecode language=&amp;lsquo;css&amp;rsquo;]Could not get database version from the Oracle Server component. The CEP file rdbmsup.sql does not provide the version directive&lt;/p>
&lt;p>and&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Start of root element expected. Upgrade Configuration file
&amp;lsquo;C:\Oracle10g2\cfgtoollogs\dbua\test\upgrade5\upgrade.xml&amp;rsquo; is not a valid XML file.[/sourcecode]&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>